Hello and welcome to our video on cross-border logistics for Amazon Selling Partners.
This video focuses on logistics when expanding to any store outside of Europe.
In this video, we will delve into the key topics of international shipping, import and export trade
and navigating customs regulations.
We'll also explore how Amazon services, like fulfillment by Amazon, FBA, Amazon Global Logistics,
AGL, and the partnered carrier program.
PCP can simplify your cross-border operations.
Let's get started.
What do I need to know before
sending my products?
You must understand the legal requirements and documentation involved
in importing goods into a foreign market or exporting products from your home country.
We recommend that you check if you are allowed to sell your products in your destination
store and what additional certificates, testing or documentation you might need beforehand.
Import duties and taxes vary from country to country and are typically charged based on
the value of the imported goods.
When shipping goods, it is important to account
for import fees, also known as delivery-duty-paid.
You can ask either your logistic provider
for support or contact an external service provider from our service provider network.
Ensuring accurate and complete customs documentation is vital for the efficient clearance of your
shipments.
Amazon's Seller Central provides guidance on customs documentation, including
commercial invoices, packing lists and certificates of origin.
Properly completing these documents facilitates the smooth flow of your shipments through
customs.
Customs brokers can support you with customs procedures.
If you need help finding
a customs broker, you can do so on the service provider network, SPN.
You can find the SPN
by going to apps and services and then explore services.
You have two options for fulfilling
worldwide orders.
First, fulfilling orders on your own, which means you are responsible
for sending products to your customers.
And second, fulfilment by Amazon FBA.
FBA is a powerful tool for cross-border logistics.
By leveraging FBA, you can store your inventory
in Amazon's global fulfilment centres.
Amazon then takes care of order processing, shipping
and customer service, helping you to offer fast and reliable fulfilment to your international
customers.
This helps you compete with domestic selling partners on delivery speed.
To ship
your products into our fulfilment network for FBA, you have three options.
First, using
your own courier.
Second, using the Amazon Partner Carrier programme, PCP.
The programme
enables you to send small parcels.
Please note this is only available for specific countries.
You can find more information on our help pages.
Or third, using Amazon Global Logistics, AGL, which supports selling partners with sending
shipments from CN to the US, UK and Europe.
If you wish to find a third-party courier,
check out the service provider network where you will find international shipping companies
who support your shipping route.
When creating a shipping plan, you get an address, an Amazon
fulfilment centre in your destination store, to where you send your shipment.
In practice, it's no different to sending a shipment to any address worldwide.
AGL offers FBA selling partners a comprehensive shipping solution from China to the US, UK
and Europe via Air and Ocean.
This service ships directly from China into our fulfilment
centres or your own warehouses.
Selling partners can select this service when creating a shipment
on Seller Central or Shipper Central.
The AGL service includes shipment pick up in origin,
palletization, if required, export import customs clearance and domestic delivery in
the destination country to either FBA or your warehouse.
We also offer the Amazon partnered carrier programme PCP for selling partners who, for
example, wish to ship directly from the UK or Germany to the US.
This programme offers
an integrated small parcel shipping service through Seller Central with automated booking,
tracking and payment.
Using this programme, you can replenish inventory on Seller Central
without needing to sort out shipping options offline.
Please check our help pages for
other locales.
You can create your shipment into FBA on Seller Central using our shipment
creation workflow.
To get started, go to your Seller Central, navigate to inventory,
FBA inventory, shipments and then send to Amazon.
First, provide your ship from address
and indicate whether you will be shipping individual or case-packed items.
Then enter
the quantities for each item and decide whether you will prep the units or you would like
Amazon to prep them for you, for a per unit fee.
We have a more extensive guide on packaging,
prep and labelling requirements in Seller University for the US.
How to ship your products from
EU to US.
If you handle returns on your own, you either need a prepaid shipping label or
a domestic return address in your destination store.
If you use fulfilment by Amazon, Amazon
takes care of your returns and inventory removal.
Amazon offers resources and tools, such as
the returns and refunds policies and the Seller Central help and customer service, to help
you handle returns and provide excellent customer support across borders.
You now have a deeper
understanding of cross-border logistics for Amazon selling partners.
Remember to explore
the resources available on Seller Central and leverage services like FBA, AgL or PCP to
streamline your operations.
By effectively managing your logistics and complying with customs
regulations, you can expand your business globally and reach customers around the world.
If you
have any further questions or need additional assistance, make sure to utilise the resources
provided by Seller Central, the Seller University and Global Selling pages that you can find
under the link, sell.
amazon.
co.
uk.
Thanks for watching and happy selling in the Amazon store.
[
MUSIC PLAYING]